ARMEL YARA

<u>LinkedIn</u> | 438-871-9767 | <u>armel.yara@umontreal.ca</u> | Montreal, Quebec

About me

Msc Bioinformatic student, I have an experience in software development with JavaScript, Flutter and data science with Python. I'm Machine Learning and Deep Learning enthusiast by solving biology challenges in healthcare. I'm looking opportunity to learn more and solving problems in biology.

Skills ___

- Programming Languages: HTML/CSS | JavaScript | Python | SQL | Linux
- Frameworks and technologies: Flutter | Bootstrap | TensorFlow | Google Cloud Platform | ScikitLearn | Keras
- Concepts: Relational Databases | non-relational databases
- Languages : French | Anglais

Work Experiences _____

Software development

09/2017 - Today

Freelance | Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

- Design mobile app for road security alerts with PWA and deployed with Firebase.
- Design mobile app(FrontEnd) for Malaria prevention with Flutter
- Design OCR API for financial service with Python Flask and deployed with Cloud Run.

Data scientist 12/2019 - 11/2023

FUTURAFRIC IA | Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

1. MALARIA PREVENTION PROJECT:

- > Work on designing Machine Learning model recommendation with TensorFlow,
- > Build Machine Learning model to recognition malaria symptoms in eyes with DeepFace,
- > To collect, processing and to store data and deploy Machine Learning model on Google Cloud Platform

2. RESUME ENGINE PROJECT:

- > Work on designing Machine Learning model to match resumes and job offers with ScikitLearn,
- Machine Learning model for recommendation for help candidates to improve their resumes.

Data scientist

Personal project | Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire

1. DR GREEN PROJECT:

- Design a Machine Learning model for medicinal plants classification with TensorFlow/Keras and Vertex AI,
- Design web app with python Flask API and deployed on Google Cloud Platform with Cloud Run.
- 2. HORUS EYES PROJECT: Design a web app for objects recognition with YOLO and Python.

Education			
Bioinformatics	Montreal University	Montreal, Quebec	1/2024 -
Computer science Bachelor	Agitel Formation	Abidjan, Côte d'Ivoire	1/2015 - 10/2017
Certification			
Google TensorFlow Developer	TensorFlow Credentials		9/2021
Data scientist with Python	Datacamp		30/2022
Machine Learning	Kaggle		8/2021
Data Engineering, Big Data, and Machine Learning on GCP	Coursera		6/2019
	Credentials		
Machine Learning on Google Cloud	Coursera		12/2019
	<u>Credentials</u>		